<?xml version='1.0'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\..\readme.xsl"?>

<sample>
<title>Find Type Class Browser Sample</title>
<title-short>FindType</title-short>
<overview>
This sample utility provides the user with a command line interface to provide information about types in their environment. Sometimes locating a specific type can be difficult (what namespace is it in, which DLL?) and once you have located the type - the documentation may be unavailable or it is out of date. This utility provides a simple way for a developer to determine what types are available, what module they are in and what interfaces, methods, fields, properties and events are available on the type. This sample also provides a peek into reflection.
</overview>
<subdirectory>Applications\TypeFinder</subdirectory>
<buildsteps>
   <step>
      Type <richcontent bold="T">BUILD.bat</richcontent>
      <richcontent> from the command line.</richcontent>      
      <example>
         C:\Program Files\Microsoft.NET\SDK\v1.1\Samples\Applications\TypeFinder\VB>Build.bat
      </example>
   </step>   
</buildsteps>
<runsteps>   
   <step>
      Type <b>FindType.exe</b> from the command line for a complete list of command line options for the utility.
      <example>
         C:\Program Files\Microsoft.NET\SDK\v1.1\Samples\Applications\TypeFinder\VB>FindType.exe
      </example>
   </step>
   <step>
      To find the location of each type with a word in its name type <b>FindType.exe [word]</b> from the command line.
      <example>
         C:\Program Files\Microsoft.NET\SDK\v1.1\Samples\Applications\TypeFinder\VB>FindType.exe String         
      </example>
   </step>
</runsteps>
<technologies>
   <technology name = "Reflection" keyword="T">      
      <class name = "Assembly" keyword="T">
      Used to load assemblies into the AppDomain so that they can be searched for types. 
      </class> 
      <class name = "Module" keyword="T">
      Used to get types from the Assembly/Module for comparison to the search string. 
      </class>
      <class name = "Type" keyword="T">
      Used to get type information such as its name, namespace, and members. 
      </class> 
      <class name = "PropertyInfo" keyword="T">
      To find information about properties in types. 
      </class> 
      <class name = "EventInfo" keyword="T">
      Used to find information about events in types. 
      </class> 
      <class name = "FieldInfo" keyword="T">
      Finds information about fields in types. 
      </class> 
      <class name = "MethodInfo" keyword="T">
      Used to finds information about methods in types. 
      </class> 
   </technology>
   <technology name = "IO" keyword="T">
      <class name = "TextWriter" keyword="T">
      Used by the IndentedWriter sample type to output (to the console, by default) in a generic fashion. 
      </class> 
   </technology>
   <technology name = "Text" keyword="T">
      <class name = "StringBuilder" keyword="T">
      Used by the IndentedWriter sample type create a string. 
      </class> 
      <class name = "String" keyword="T">
      Used throughout the sample to find format strings, find sub-strings, upper-case strings etc. 
      </class> 
   </technology>
   <technology name = "Collections" keyword="T">      
      <class name = "ArrayList" keyword="T">
      Used by the sample to manage a growable list of strings. 
      </class> 
   </technology>
   <technology name = "Registry" keyword="T">      
      <class name = "Registry" keyword="T">
      Used to create an instance of the RegistryKey type for a subkey of the LocalMachine key.
      </class> 
      <class name = "RegistryKey" keyword="T">
      Used to read values from a key in the registry.
      </class> 
   </technology>
</technologies>
</sample>



